Tourette syndrome is a medical condition  that  people live within their daily lives  they make involuntary sounds known as  tics it could be a sound or a movement  that the body cannot control I have this  one sometimes I click my tongue in the  back of my throat like this but not very  awesome and I constantly crack my  knuckles even if I did so they mostly  mostly would ask me like like why like  like why I'm lying my eyes keep  twitching or like we're asking or asking  me if like my let if I can stop like  moving might like the tics the ticks  were more that were more like the head  shaking as well barking I started taking  went for a while where I just stepped  backwards and walked backwards for a  couple of steps and then walk back I had  to take once when I was when I'd be  standing and I'd lift up my leg when I  was first diagnosed I was out of school  for weeks my tics were very high there  my vocal tics were elevated my motor  tics would really hurt me it was tough  you know  seven or so years old I was responding  well is this just gonna keep on no  hunger they like singled me out and and  tree didn't me more as you know it  basically almost as I was like an alien  in a sense and in it because at that  point in time I didn't really understand  much about what was happening you have a  seven year old when I take him to school  and I go down the elevator right before  we got on the elevator I'll take my  teeth and I'll bang my teeth against the  wall and he asked me what are you doing  dad so I said oh I have Suresh syndrome  is a condition that causes me to do  things I don't want to do and so it's  the funny thing is the other day he  comes up to me and we're standing there  and I don't  the elevator and he said it's a t8 into  your Tourette's and I'm like no it's not  it's not like that it didn't work that  way it's hard to suppress a dick and  even if you do suppress a tick when  you're done suppressing the tick they  only come out more I have some morph my  words instead of saying Bom Bom Bom I go  pop pop if I try to suppress them they  it doesn't work that's like trying to  hold in a sneeze young girls would laugh  kind of embarrassing for an adult to be  bullied by a young teenagers as a young  kid I would I you know take whatever it  was and immediately look around to see  who who noticed you know like as if it  really mattered and then so then you  really start to believe that you are  different I would be out on the subway  and attracting attention from other  people adults and like learning about  how cruel people can be seeing those  kids in DC at the conference treating  their tics as as something that was just  you know part of who they are was so  inspiring it's really cool kids don't  get judged there and they have fun with  other kids like them other than our tics  were normal or normal people because  everyone has their own things that may  then make them different from one  another and threats interests happens to  be one of those things for some people  don't be afraid of people with  disabilities just because someone has a  disability doesn't mean that you have to  avoid them I think the Tourette  Association of America means support and  community my hope is that everyone who  sees this video goes home and tells  three people about Tourette's syndrome  you