Attention-deficit/hyperactivity disorder, or ADHD,
is a condition characterized by difficulties with
attention and/or hyperactivity and impulsivity.
ADHD involves strong genetic influences, but
environmental factors, and interactions between
genetics and the environment, are thought
to play an important role in ADHD as well.
Much of the recent research into the neuroscience
of ADHD has focused on understanding the brain
networks that might underlie different
aspects of cognitive function in ADHD.
One example is the default mode network,
which is a collection of brain regions
that is more active during mind-wandering and
introspection, and less active when a person
is attempting to complete a specific task.
Studies have found that people with ADHD have
atypical connectivity in the default mode network,
which might be associated with distractibility.
Individuals with ADHD also display
lower activity in brain networks
that are involved in attention and cognitive
control. Typically, activity in these networks
increases when activity in the default
mode network decreases, and vice versa.
Thus, one hypothesis is that in ADHD activity
in the default mode network is dysregulated
and interferes with the function of networks
involved in attention and cognitive control.
Studies have also found that people with ADHD tend
to display atypical activity in the reward system,
a group of structures that are
involved in motivated behavior,
anticipation, and reinforced learning.
This atypical reward system activity
might be associated with a tendency to
overestimate the value of short-term rewards
in comparison to long-term rewards, which
could also affect planning and decision-making.
The reward system includes some of the major
dopamine pathways in the brain, and dopamine is
often implicated in ADHD because medications that
are commonly used to treat the condition, such as
amphetamine and methylphenidate, cause increased
transmission of dopamine and norepinephrine.