Autism, also known as autism spectrum disorder,
is characterized by symptoms that include
impairments in social communication and interaction
and restricted and repetitive behaviors.
Although the neuroscience of autism is still
poorly understood, autism is considered to
be a complex developmental disorder that involves
atypical brain organization starting early
in development.
Individuals with autism often experience a
period of unusually rapid brain growth in
infancy and early childhood.
This accelerated brain growth is linked to
an atypical pattern of connectivity between
brain regions.
A number of studies report that alterations
in brain circuitry involved with social interaction
and attention can be detected well before
the symptoms of autism begin to appear.
At this point, however, it’s unclear how
brain overgrowth and atypical connectivity
might be linked to the occurrence of autism
symptoms.
Research suggests that the risk of autism
is strongly influenced by genetics, yet studies
consistently report that environmental factors
also play a large role.
Although a number of potential environmental
factors have been identified, the risk factors
for autism are far from definitive, and it
remains unclear which factors are responsible
for causing an increase in autism risk, and
which are associated in a non-causal way.
The risk factors that are most strongly linked
to autism are associated with the prenatal
or perinatal period.
Thus, it’s possible they might be responsible
for disruptions to typical neural development,
leading to symptoms of autism months or years
later.
How these risk factors might interfere with
neural development is still uncertain, but
hypotheses have suggested potential mechanisms
such as epigenetic effects, inflammation,
oxidative stress, or damage caused by oxygen
deficiency.
More work needs to be done, however, to fully
elucidate the genetic and environmental risk
factors for autism, as well as the mechanisms
for the development of autism symptoms.